CHRISTOPHER E. FRANKLIN

NEWINGTON, CT 06111 | (860)836-9933 | cef1911@hotmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/christopherefranklin

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Results Driven Software Developer with working proficiency in multiple web design and development, software languages, such as Java, JavaScript, C#, Angular, Amazon Web Services, HTML, PHP, CSS, Android Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, building cross platform mobile/web applications. Cloud Computing, Azure DevOPs, Tidal Workload Automation, Batch Scripting, MVC, SQL Server, ASP.net, C#, KendoUI, Python with Data Science, Machine Learning, Robotics with Python Programming concentration.

Currently studying Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Scientist Associate Certification Training. Created and working on an open-source data science project with several developers across the world. Project endpoints are a Credit Card Fraud Detection solution. Additional open-source projects planned on our timeline.

Expert in cultivating relationships from over 23 years working in an award-winning sales and management career. Accustomed to working in deadline driven, fast paced, and multi-tasking environments. 2019 Master's Degree with concentration Mobile Application Development graduated with 3.86 GPA.

SKILLS

Programming Experience: C#, .NET, Java, Python, Angular, Hybrid Mobile Applications, Cross Platform Mobile Applications, JavaScript, Go, JSON, PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Lua, Zapier, Shopify, IntelliJ Software, Visual Basic **Design, Frameworks, and IDE Tools:** Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, XML, Adobe PhoneGap Build, Apache Cordova,

Android Studio, Sublime Text

Database Management: SQL Server, SSRS, Oracle, RDBMS, MySQL Workbench

Cloud Computing: Amazon Alexa Skills, RDS, DynamoDB, Lambda, S3, IAM, EC2, VPCs, CloudTrail, CloudFormation

Version Control: BitBucket, Jira, Git, TFS

Reporting and Automation: Tidal Workload Automation & Enterprise Job Scheduling Software

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Denver, CO, Cumulative GPA 3.86

Master of Science: Mobile Application Development

March 2019

Certificate in Web Design and Development

June 2018

Relevant Coursework: Native Application Development with Adobe Air on Mobile Devices,

Mobile App Development, Web Development with PHP, Advanced Web Design and Management

Capstone Project: Mobile Applications that go viral should follow specific strategies to achieve a status of sustainable

mass adoption

University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT

Bachelor of General Studies: Corporate and Organizational Studies

June 2006

Branford Hall Career Institute, Branford, CT, graduated President's List GPA 3.86 CompTIA A+, NET +, INET + Certifications: Software and Network Administration

July 2002

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Voya Investment Management

May 2020-Present

Application Developer, Windsor, CT

- Lead Developer on a multiple month Database Upgrade from SQL Server 2012 to a Azure Fully Managed Platform as a Service(Paas) Database
- Adroitly fixes time-sensitive SQL Server production issues by modifying stored procedures, functions, tables, and views
- Creates and maintains multiple sftp upload processes using WinSCP SSH File Transfer Protocol, batch file scripting, and Tidal Workload Automation Software
- Performs and supports all aspects of the Software Development Life Cycle, including problem investigation, business analysis, design, implementation, maintenance, and support, as part of our technology team focused on support of our Voya Investment Management (IM) organization.
- Builds a strong rapport with the investment teams, operations personnel, and information technology team members.
- Involvement with implementation of longer-term projects as well as smaller project tasks.
- Provides business day user support for applications developed and supported by our team.
- Works quickly to understand how each application functions in order to troubleshoot issues, figure out appropriate
 resolution, and communicate resolution clearly with our customer base which includes portfolio managers,
 investment professionals and operations staff.
- On call on a periodic rotational basis to support processes loading financial information overnight that is required for the start of the business day.
- Develops and create appropriate test plans, working directly with customers to determine requirements and solutions for tasks.

Employee Family Protection

January 2020-May 2020

Jr. Software Developer, Glastonbury, CT

- Executed code fix projects using Visual Studio with the .NET framework and C#.
- Completed code modifications to address Internet Explorer incompatibility issues using ¡Query, HTML, C#, and .NET.
- Performed Quality Assurance Testing of software applications to prepare for production environment deployment.
- Fixed a HTML user input issue by refactoring the HTML code for our customer-facing benefit administration web application.
- Refactored code for a Front-End Web Application calculation issue utilizing MySQL Workbench, C#, HTML, and JavaScript.

- Developed information systems working with Product Management; designing, developing, and testing software solutions. Applies best industry practices to software development and the entire SDLC.
- Developed software solutions by studying software design specifications; conferring with users; studying systems. flow, data usage, and work processes; investigating problem areas; following the software development lifecycle.
- Determined operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions.
- Documented and demonstrated solutions by developing documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments and clear code.

Volunteer Web Developer(Non-Paid)

April 2018-Present

Website Designer, Remote-position, Hartford, CT

- Creates website for The Tau Iota Chapter of The Omega Psi Phi Fraternity, Inc.
- Manages and drives sales for an online website store that generates thousands of dollars for community impacting fundraising initiatives
- Utilizes Google Analytics web analytics service to track and report website traffic
- Maintains website design regularly.
- URL: https://www.tauiotaques.org/

Co-Chair of First District Website and Tech Committee of The Omega Psi Phi Fraternity, Inc.

April 2019-Present

- Maintains and collaborates with a committee of IT and Security Professionals on Website and Tech projects
- Creates stunning webpages that interface with multiple Eventbrite events for customer impacting activities
- Coaches currently four District-wide chapters on website creation and maintenance
- URL: <u>www.firstdistrictoppf.org</u>

ES360LLC June 2018-November 2018

Remote Software Developer, Washington D.C. Metro Area

- Utilized the Lua programming language to create ecommerce software for food truck solution
- Established Zapier web-based end-user integrations for ecommerce project
- Created Shopify API web-integrations using web-hooks

Verizon Wireless November 1996-January 2020

Solution Specialist, North Haven, CT

March 2014-January 2020

- Mentored Directed team to rank of 4th out of 88 locations in New England Region 3rd quarter 2014 total mobile protection sales
- Mentored new hires on proven sales techniques that garner results
- 2nd rank out of 1089 Solution Specialists in January 2015
- Demonstrated high levels of performance by achieving annual net quota attainment of 141% in 2014
- Exhibited sales excellence shown by attaining annual sales commission revenue of 110% in 2014
- Expertise in driving customers to retail stores for instore customer sales engagements through phone calls and ditigal campaigns tools

Retail Store Manager, Various Locations, CT

October 2006-February 2014

- Hired, developed, and evaluated all store personnel on location operation processes and sales metrics
- Launched and taught district wide sales performance program to drive continuous profitability improvements
- Trained Southern New England Region Retail Store new hires on commission sales
- Promoted employee as Senior Sales Representative to Assistant Store Manager in 10 months
- Exhibited sound judgment while executing team coaching responsibilities and functions
- Advised and prepared team leaders on interviewing for prospective career promotions
- Cross-trained and backed up other New England region stores and indirect agent managers
- Expertise in driving customers to retail stores for instore customer sales engagements through phone calls and ditigal campaigns tools
- Worked directly with local chamber of commerce organizations to increase business traffic and store profits

Assistant Store Manager, Various Locations, CT

July 2003-September 2006

- Instructed staff on appropriately handling and complicated issues
- Developed positive relationships with mall management and mall stores to increase sales

Retail Sales Representative, Various Locations, CT

November 1996-June 2003

- Trained teammates on how to effectively use the Retail Customer Outbound Calling Program
- Generated high levels of incremental sales by executing an effective follow-up program
- Developed highly empathetic client relationships and earned a reputation for exceeding service standard goals
- Expertise in driving customers to retail stores for instore customer sales engagements through phone calls and mailing campaigns

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Creates and works on an open-source data science project with developers worldwide(Non-Paid) March 2021-Present

- Project endpoints are a Credit Card Fraud Detection Solution
- Utilizes Anaconda Data Science Platform
- Uses CookieCutter Data Science Environment Template
- Recruits Group contributors though Facebook Python and Data Science Groups
- Establishes Signal App Communication Group
- Updates and leads team on Deadline Milestones, Action Items and Software Requirements to participate
- Creates and modifies GitHub DevOps structure
- Kaggle Source code idea from https://towardsdatascience.com/12-cool-data-science-projects-ideas-for-beginners-and-experts-fc75b5498e03

Completes Multiple Month Robotics with Python Programming Sessions with Mentor(Non-Paid) March 2021-Present

- Successfully runs and debugs multiple programs using Firialabs.com MicroBit device with Python programming
- Utilizes CodeSpace Learning Environment
- On-going structured weekly sessions: Proficiency in Robotics and Python is the planned endpoint

- Imports various libraries and utilized functions such as display.show, display.scroll, music.play and passing parameters
- Proper variable use/syntax and implementation use of functions sleep and delay
- Debugs through stepping through code
- GitHub Repository https://github.com/cef1911/CodeSpace-MicroBit-Modules

Pluralsight Course: Doing Data Science with Python(Non-Paid)

March 2021-Present

- Understands Data Science Project Cycle, Anaconda Distribution, Jupyter Notebook Basics
- Extracts Magic Functions, and Extracting Data from Databases
- GitHub Repository https://github.com/cef1911/jupyternotebooksqllite

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Scientist Associate Training(Non-Paid)

March 2021-Present

- Completes Data Science and Machine Learning Module
- Learns R, Python, and Tableau curriculum
- Sets up an Azure Machine Learning workspace
- · Runs experiments and train models
- Optimizes and manages models
- · Deploys and consumes model
- Explores data arrays with NumPY
- Ignite on Microsoft Learn | Microsoft Docs

Builds Mobile Application for Omega Psi Phi Fraternity, Inc.(Non-Paid)

October 2019-present

- Builds mobile application for local fraternity chapter. Technologies used: Java and Android Studio
- Will be utilized by local members as a strategic correspondence tool to enhance community service initiatives
- GitHub Repository https://github.com/cef1911/AndroidMobileAppCommunityOrganization

Builds To Do List Web Application(Non-Paid)

November 2019-present

- Creates Web Application as activity completion tool. Technologies used: PHP, HTML, phpMyAdmin, and MySQL
- Employs CRUD grid (Create, Read, Write, Delete)

Built Flashlight Mobile Application during course at Manchester Community College

October 2019-December 2019

- Built in HTML, CSS, JavaScript as a container then packaged to use with Android OS distributed through APK Employs CRUD grid (Create, Read, Write, Delete)
- GitHub Repository https://github.com/cef1911/WatzThisApp
- GitHub Repository https://github.com/cef1911/WatzThisMobileAppzip

Other GitHub Repositories:

https://github.com/cef1911/JavaExamples

https://github.com/cef1911/Chris Fishing Website

https://github.com/cef1911/JQueryRemoveAddButton

https://github.com/cef1911/AngularSnippets

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Omega Psi Phi Fraternity Inc., Tau Iota Chapter Omega Man Of The Year Award Recipient 2020

Omega Psi Phi Fraternity Inc., Tau Iota Chapter Superior Service Award Recipient 2017

#1 Verizon Wireless Solutions Specialist in Accessory Revenue in District May 2019

Four Aces Sales Award: January 2015

Led Store to #3 ranking out of 376 stores in the Northeast Region in Softcard/ISIS Mobile Payment Sales: February 2014

Directed Team to #1 ranking out of 33 stores in Comcast Referral Sales: August 2013

#1 Verizon Wireless Store Sales Ranking New England Region: July 2013

Verizon Wireless President's Leadership Challenge Winner: 2013

#1 Verizon Wireless Store Sales Ranking New England Region: 2010

Won Verizon Wireless Store Sales Award Southern New England Region Peak Performer Distinction 5 quarters in a row

Verizon Wireless Winner's Circle Sales Award: 2006, 2002 Verizon Wireless President's Cabinet Sales Award 1997